effectualservices.com 2013-11-03

# Privacy Policy | Effectual Service

**Your Privacy on** EffectualServices.com

This website is administered by Effectual Services. The primary purpose of Effectual Services is to innovating solutions for assisting you to achieve your future goals. At Effectual Services, we respect and appreciate the confidentiality of all information provided to us. This policy explains the information Effectual Services gathers from visitors to our website at http://www.effectualservices.com, how the information is gathered, and how such information is used.

**How information is gathered?**

Information on Effectual Services is collected in two ways:  
(1) Indirectly and (2) Directly.

An example of information collected indirectly is through our web access logs. When you access Effectual Services, your Internet Protocol (IP) address is automatically placed in our web logs. And an example of information collected directly is when you provide information on various web pages of Effectual Services.

We collect information from you directly in many ways, some of which we describe in this Privacy Statement. One way is through the use of cookies. Cookies are small parcels of information that our website sends to your browser when you access Effectual Services. Cookies are used to track user preferences. For example, the information that interest you the most, your entry path to our site and how you navigate. You may choose to disable cookies on your computer by changing the setting preferences or options menu in your browser.

We also collect information from you when you voluntarily submit to us. Throughout our website, we provide the opportunity to register for an event or conference, our newsletter, order an article/white paper, and participate in an online survey or a recent blog post.

**How do we use this Information?**  
We analyze the information collected to find out what is effective about our site, to help us identify ways to improve it, and finally, to determine how we can tailor Effectual Services to make it more effective for you. We may also use personal information collected for purposes which we explain to you at the time we collect the information.

Information collected includes:

A. **IP Address:** We may use your IP address (for example, it may look something like this: 192.0.0.1) to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. We may also use your IP address to identify the time you spend on our site and to gather broad demographic information. This allows us to see which parts of our site users are visiting. We do not associate IP addresses with anything personally identifiable which means a user’s session will be tracked, but the user will remain anonymous.

B. **Personal Information:** We will notify you when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you. This information is generally requested when you register for our newsletter or submit your first name, last name, and email through an inquiry or feedback form on our website. We use personal information so collected only to initiate contact with you to the extent required.

**Will we share this with outside parties?**  
As a global organization, data we collect may be transferred internationally throughout Effectual Services worldwide organization. We will not sell, rent or distribute any individual information and will share it only with our advisors. There will be other times when we need to share information. But again, before you submit any information, we will notify you as to why we are asking for specific information and it is completely up to you whether or not you want to provide it.

Only Effectual Services employees and authorized agents can access the personal information collected via our Website. All such persons are bound by confidentiality agreements and may be subject to discipline, up to and including termination for violating any terms of the confidentiality agreements.

**What about sensitive personal data?**  
We do not generally seek to collect sensitive personal data through this site. If we do seek to collect such data, we will ask you to consent to our proposed uses of the data. We may also collect some sensitive personal data incidentally. By providing us with unsolicited sensitive personal data, you consent to our using the data subject to applicable law as described in this Privacy Statement. The references to sensitive personal data are to the various categories of personal data identified by European and other data privacy laws that requires special treatment, including in some circumstances the need to obtain explicit consent. These categories comprise personal identity numbers, personal data about personality and private life, racial or ethnic origin, nationality, political opinions, membership of political parties or movements, religious, philosophical or other similar beliefs, membership of a trade union or profession or trade association, physical or mental health, genetic code, addictions, sexual life, property matters or criminal record (including information about suspected criminal activities).

**Do we give you access to your information?**  
You are entitled to know whether we hold information about you and, if we do, to have access to that information and require it to be corrected if it is inaccurate. You can do this by sending us an e-mail.

**Links to Other sites**  
Our Website may contain links to other websites. Effectual Services is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites. We encourage you to review the relevant privacy policies before you provide any personal information.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
You can opt out of receiving e-mail communications from us whenever you like. You only need to e-mail us to have your name and details removed from Effectual Services e-mail list or registration database.

To change or delete your information, you can send an email to [privacy@effectualservices.com](mailto:privacy@effectualservices.com). This e-mail address is being protected from spam bots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it. Within a reasonable period of time thereafter, we will change or delete the information, as the case may be.

**Amendments**  
We may amend this policy, from time to time, by posting a revised policy on our Website. We encourage you to review this page for any updates to this policy.

**Contact**  
For any questions, comments or suggestions pertaining to our privacy policy you may write to us at [privacy@effectualservices.com](mailto:privacy@effectualservices.com). This e-mail address is being protected from spam bots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
